<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>地城世界 HTML SRD</title>
    <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 地城世界 HTML SRD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/license/</guid>
      <description>License This work is licensed under the Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 Unported License. To view a copy of this license, visit http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/ or send a letter to Creative Commons, 444 Castro Street, Suite 900, Mountain View, California, 94041, USA.
DESIGNATION OF OPEN GAME CONTENT The following monsters are open game content: Aboleth Ankheg Assassin Vine Barbed Devil Black Pudding Blink Dog Bulette Chain Devil Choker Chuul Cloaker Coutal Devourer Digester Dragon Turtle Ethereal Filcher Flesh Golem Formian Centurion Formian Drone Formian Queen Formian Taskmaster Gelatinous Cube Girallaon Gnoll Alpha Gnoll Emissary Gnoll Tracker Gray Render Inevitable Iron Golem Magmin Mohrg Otyugh Owlbear Purple Worm Quasit Razor Boar Roper Rot Grub Rust Monster Sahuagin Tarrasque Treant Triton Noble Triton Spy Triton Sub-Mariner Triton Tidecaller Troglodyte</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Delving</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/advanced_delving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/advanced_delving/</guid>
      <description>Advanced DelvingDungeon World portrays a specific kind of fantasy adventure—one with elves and dwarves, heroes and villains, and characters struggling for riches and glory in a dangerous world. Maybe you’ve got an idea for something different—maybe your Dungeon World is set on a blasted desert planet, peopled by savage cannibals and ruled by haughty psychics. Or maybe you want to play a game where humans are the only race available, but they belong to clans or families as different from each other as a gnome is from a dwarf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adventure Conversion</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/conversion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/conversion/</guid>
      <description>Adventure ConversionThere isn’t always time for prep. People aren’t entirely committed to a game—you just want to test it out or you’ve got a four-hour slot at a convention that you want to fill and you’ve never met the players before in your life. Maybe prep isn’t something you care about or you think it’s more fun to just take a map and run with it. Even better, maybe you’ve got a favorite old school adventure module and you’d love to run through using the Dungeon World rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Session</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/first_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/first_session/</guid>
      <description>First SessionThe first session of a game of Dungeon World begins with character creation. Character creation is also world creation, the details on the character sheets and the questions that you ask establish what Dungeon World is like—who lives in it and what’s going on.
This section is for the GM so it’s addressed to you—the GM. For the players, the first session is just like every other. They just have to play their characters like real people and explore Dungeon World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fronts</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/fronts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/fronts/</guid>
      <description>FrontsFronts are secret tomes of GM knowledge. Each is a collection of linked dangers—threats to the characters specifically and to the people, places, and things the characters care about. It also includes one or more impending dooms, the horrible things that will happen without the characters’ intervention. “Fronts” comes, of course, from “fighting on two fronts” which is just where you want the characters to be—surrounded by threats, danger and adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant NPCs</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/npcs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/npcs/</guid>
      <description>Instant NPCsSometimes the players will come across someone who becomes important in the moment. When the ritual goes wrong and a poor captive gets the power cosmic what does that villager do with it? Who were they?
When you need a quick NPC all you need is an instinct and some way to pursue it. We call that a knack, it can be anything from a skill to a title to a debt owed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower Depths</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</guid>
      <description>Lower DepthsAboleth	Group, Huge, IntelligentTentacle (d10+3 damage), 18 HP, 0 Armor
Reach
Special Qualities: Telepathy
Deep below the surface of the world, in freshwater seas untouched by the sun, dwell the aboleth. Fish the size of whales, with strange growths of gelatinous feelers used to probe the lightless shores. They’re served by slaves: blind albino victims of any race unfortunate enough to stumble on them, drained of thought and life by the powers of the aboleth’s alien mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monsters</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</guid>
      <description>MonstersGreat heroes need horrendous antagonists. This section is about how to create and play as those antagonists—from the lowly goblin warrior to the hellish demon.
Using MonstersA monster is any living (or undead) thing that stands in the characters’ way.
How you use these monsters follows directly from your agenda and principles. Stay true to your principles, use your moves and pursue your agenda—you can’t go wrong. Your first agenda is to portray a fantastic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moves in Detail</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/class_moves_discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/class_moves_discussion/</guid>
      <description>Moves in DetailMulticlass MovesMulticlass DabblerMulticlass InitiateMulticlass MasterFor the purposes of these multiclass moves the cleric’s commune and cast a spell count as one move. Likewise for the wizard’s spellbook, prepare Spells, and cast a Spell.
When you first select a multiclass move that grants you the ability to cast spells you prepare and cast spells as if you had one level in the casting class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planar Powers</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</guid>
      <description>Planar PowersAngel	Solitary, Terrifying, Divine, Intelligent, OrganizedSword of Flames (b[2d10]+4 damage, ignores armor), 18 HP, 4 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Wings
“So was it written that the heavens opened up to Avra’hal and did an angel from the clouds emerge to speak unto her and so did it appear to her as her firstborn daughter—beautiful, of ebon skin and golden eyes—and did Avra’hal weep to see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Playing the Game</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/playing_the_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/playing_the_game/</guid>
      <description>Playing the GamePlaying Dungeon World means having a conversation; somebody says something, then you reply, maybe someone else chimes in. We talk about the fiction—the world of the characters and the things that happen around them. As we play, the rules will chime in, too. They have something to say about the world. There are no turns or rounds in Dungeon World, no rules to say whose turn it is to talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravenous Hordes</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</guid>
      <description>Ravenous HordesFormian Drone	Horde, Organized, CautiousBite (d6 damage), 7 HP, 4 Armor
Close
Special Qualities: Hive connection, Insectoid
With good cause, they say that these creatures (like all insects, really) are claimed by the powers of Law. They are order made flesh—a perfectly stratified society in which every larva, hatchling and adult knows its place in the great hive. The formian is some strange intersection of men and ants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Denizens</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</guid>
      <description>Swamp DenizensBakunawa	Solitary, Large, Intelligent, Messy, ForcefulBite (d10+3 damage, 1 piercing), 16 HP, 2 Armor
Close, Reach
Special Qualities: Amphibious
Dragon-Turtle’s sister is a mighty serpent queen. Ten yards of scales and muscle, they say she wakes with a hunger when the sun disappears from the sky. She is attracted by bright light in the darkness and like any snake, the Bakunawa is sneaky. She will seek first to beguile and mislead and will only strike out with violence when no other option is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching the Game</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/appendices/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Teaching the GameSince you’ve read this book it’s likely at some point you’ll be teaching the game to others, either experienced roleplayers or those new to the hobby. Throughout the design process we’ve had many chances to play with lots of different gamers from different backgrounds and there are a few things we’ve found work well for teaching the game.
Pitch ItBefore you play you’ll likely be explaining the game to your new players (don’t just spring it on them, that’s not cool).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GM</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/basics/</guid>
      <description>The GMThere are many different fantasy genres, each with their own style or advice for GMing. Dungeon World is designed for one of those styles in particular—a world of elves, orcs, dragons and magic where dark dangers mix with lighthearted adventure. The rules in this chapter will help you run a game in that style.
The characters have rules to follow when they roll dice and take actions. The GM has rules to follow, too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thief</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/thief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/thief/</guid>
      <description>The ThiefYou’ve heard them, sitting around the campfire. Bragging about this battle or that. About how their gods are smiling on your merry band. You count your coins and smile to yourself—this is the thrill above all. You alone know the secret of Dungeon World—filthy filthy lucre.
Sure, they give you lip for all the times you’ve snuck off alone but without you, who among them wouldn’t have been dissected by a flying guillotine or poisoned straight to death by some ancient needle trap?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/wizard/</guid>
      <description>The WizardDungeon World has rules. Not the laws of men or the rule of some petty tyrant. Bigger, better rules. You drop something—it falls. You can’t make something out of nothing. The dead stay dead, right?
Oh, the things we tell ourselves to feel better about the long, dark nights.
You’ve spent so very long poring over those tomes of yours. The experiments that nearly drove you mad and all the botched summonings that endangered your very soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The world</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/the_world/</guid>
      <description>The worldMuch of the adventuring life is spent in dusty, forgotten tombs or in places of terror and life-threatening danger. It’s commonplace to awaken from a short and fitful rest still deep in the belly of the world and surrounded by foes. When the time comes to emerge from these places—whether laden with the spoils of battle or beaten and bloody—an adventurer seeks out safety and solace.
These are the comforts of civilization: a warm bath, a meal of mead and bread, the company of fellow men and elves and dwarves and halflings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Experiments</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</guid>
      <description>Twisted ExperimentsBulette	Solitary, Huge, ConstructBite (d10+5 damage, 3 piercing), 20 HP, 3 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Burrowing
A seasoned caravan guard learns to listen for the calls of a scout or sentry with a keen ear. A few extra seconds after the alarm is raised can mean life or death. Different cries mean different responses, too—a call of “orcs!” means draw your sword and steady for blood but a call of “bandits!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undead Legions</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</guid>
      <description>Undead Legions憎惡屍魔 (Abomination)Solitary, Large, Construct, TerrifyingSlam (d10+3 damage), 20 HP, 1 Armor
Close, Reach, Forceful
Special Qualities: Many limbs, heads, and so on
Corpses sewn onto corpses make up the bulk of these shambling masses of dark magic. Most undead are crafted to be controlled—made to serve some purpose like building a tower or serving as guardians. Not so the abomination. The last aspect of the ritual used to grant fire to their hellish limbs invokes a hatred so severe that the abomination knows but one task: to tear and rend at the very thing it cannot have—life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>動作</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/moves/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/moves/</guid>
      <description>基本動作砍劈 (Hack and Slash)當你以近戰肉搏攻擊敵人時，擲+力量。✴擲出10+時，你對敵人造成傷害並避開其攻擊。你也可以選擇造成額外+1d6傷害，但將自己暴露在敵人的攻擊之下。✴擲出7-9時，你對敵人造成傷害，且敵人對你進行攻擊。
射擊 (Volley)當你瞄準並射擊遠方的敵人時，擲+敏捷。✴擲出10+時，你成功命中目標－－造成你的傷害。✴擲出7-9時，選擇下列一項（無論選擇哪一項，你都可以對其造成傷害）：
你必須移動位置才能射中目標，這將使你置身GM所決定的危險當中。你必須妥協：-1d6傷害。你必須射好幾箭，減少 1發彈藥。面對危險 (Defy Danger)當你在迫在眉睫的威脅之下採取行動或即將遭受災難性的後果，敘述你要如何處理它並擲骰。如果你……
……靠蠻力解決，擲+力量。……靠迅速行動或躲避開來，擲+敏捷。……靠耐力忍受，擲+體質。……藉由臨機應變，擲+智力。……透過堅毅的精神，擲+睿知。……使用魅力與社交禮儀，擲+魅力。✴擲出10時，你做出你預計執行的行動，該威脅不會應驗。✴擲出7-9時，你躊躇、猶豫、或退縮了：GM會給你一個更糟的後果、妥協，或是困難的抉擇。
保衛 (Defend)當你挺身保護一個遭受攻擊的人、物品、或地點時，擲+體質。✴擲出10+時，獲得 3掌握。✴擲出7-9時，獲得 1掌握。只要你仍維持保衛，當你或你的保衛對象遭受攻擊時，你可以消耗掌握，每消耗 1掌握就可以從下列選擇一項：
將針對保衛對象的攻擊導向你自己。將該攻擊的效果或傷害減半。使攻擊者露出破綻，讓一名夥伴在對付他時獲得下次+1。對攻擊者造成等同於你等級的傷害。憶述見聞 (Spout Lore)當你回憶自己積累下來，關於某個事物的知識時，擲+智力。✴擲出10+時，GM會就你的情況告訴你一件有趣且有用的情報。✴擲出7-9時，GM只會告訴你一件有趣的情報－－你必須自己設法讓它派上用場。GM可能會詢問你「你是怎麼知道的？」現在，陳述事實吧。
審視現狀 (Discern Realities)當你仔細地研究一個情景或人物時，擲+睿知：✴擲出10+時，從下列清單中選擇三個問題詢問GM。✴擲出7-9時，則只能詢問一個問題。當依據答案而採取行動時，獲得下次+1。
這裡最近發生了什麼事？這裡有什麼即將發生？我應該要注意些什麼？這裡有什麼是對我有價值或派得上用場的？誰才是掌控這裡的人？這裡有什麼與其表面所見不同？談判 (Parley)當你擁有籌碼以利用GM的角色，且打算操弄他們時，擲+魅力。這個籌碼必須是他們所需要或想要的事物。✴擲出10+時，他們會向你要求某件事，且若你先做出承諾，則他們將依你所言行事。✴擲出7-9時，他們將要求一些關於你承諾的具體保證，現在就要。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>動作 - 討論</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/moves_discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/moves_discussion/</guid>
      <description>基本動作這個章節列出了那些所有角色都能夠使用的動作。這些動作被分為兩類：基本動作和特殊動作。
基本動作是冒險者生活中的主要內容。它們涵蓋了各種在戰鬥中、緊張交涉、以及身處危險區域時可能發生的情境。特殊動作則較少發生。它們涵蓋了像是升級、長途旅行、或在冒險與冒險之間返回城鎮時發生的事情。
所有玩家角色都擁有全部的基本動作和特殊動作。每名玩家角色也都有著各自的職業動作──我們會在稍後的章節中再提及它們。
這裡介紹將先列出每個動作的名稱，接著記載該動作的相關規則。有些動作還會附帶一小段關於如何使用該動作的說明文字、以及在遊戲中實際使用的範例。
砍劈 (Hack and Slash)當你以近戰肉搏攻擊敵人時，擲+力量。✴擲出10+時，你對敵人造成傷害並避開其攻擊。你也可以選擇造成額外+1d6傷害，但將自己暴露在敵人的攻擊之下。✴擲出7-9時，你對敵人造成傷害，且敵人對你進行攻擊。
Hack and slash is for attacking a prepared enemy plain and simple. If the enemy isn’t prepared for your attack—if they don’t know you’re there or they’re restrained and helpless—then that’s not hack and slash. You just deal your damage or murder them outright, depending on the situation. Nasty stuff.
The enemy’s counterattack can be any GM move made directly with that creature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>吟遊詩人</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/bard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/bard/</guid>
      <description>吟遊詩人冒險者之詩乃是不斷向前之路，是錢幣與戰鬥的榮光。在那些鄉農滿座的酒館中被傳唱的故事，總有些許真實，對吧？那些鼓舞農民與國親的歌謠──那些撫慰野獸或讓人瘋狂的歌謠──必定其來有自。
當個詩人吧。來，帶著你的巧舌與機智。你說故事，你唱歌謠。一名尋常樂手只會複誦，而真正的吟遊詩人活在其中。繫上你的靴子吧，高貴的演說家。磨利那把小刀，接受呼喚。總得有人要與那些暴徒、惡棍與即將成為英雄的人們並肩作戰。又有誰比你更能傳誦自己的英雄故事？
沒有別人了。來吧。
名稱 (Names)精靈: Astrafel, Daelwyn, Feliana, Damarra, Sistranalle, Pendrell, Melliandre, Dagoliir
人類: Baldric, Leena, Dunwick, Willem, Edwyn, Florian, Seraphine, Quorra, Charlotte, Lily, Ramonde, Cassandra
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Knowing Eyes, Fiery Eyes, or Joyous EyesFancy Hair, Wild Hair, or Stylish CapFinery, Traveling Clothes, or Poor ClothesFit Body, Well-fed Body, or Thin Body屬性數值 (Stats)你的最大生命值為 6+體質值。
你的基礎傷害骰為 d6。
起始動作 (Starting Moves)選擇一個種族並獲得相應的動作：</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>幽暗森林</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</guid>
      <description>幽暗森林殺手藤 (Assassin Vine)單獨, 隱匿, 不定型荊棘 (d10 傷害, 1 穿透), 15 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 及遠, 毀亂
特性: 植物
在動物的世界中，狩獵者與獵物之間存在著明顯的區別。你只需一眼就能看穿－－透過那鋒利尖牙和發光眼瞳、或利爪、或毒刺－－這個世界上的某些生物就是注定要殺戮，而某些則是注定被獵殺。或許你能發現，這類差異也同樣將這個世界上的綠葉鮮花分成了兩半。在森林結社的德魯伊們清楚知曉這件事。遊俠們，也可能會在為時已晚前發現這種植物。然而，那些平民百姓，當他們徘徊在他們不應前往之處－－當他們深入爬藤蔓生的森林深處，忽然，啪噠一聲，這些飢餓的藤索緊緊纏勒，將這些肥美的獵物拖進了灌木叢中。注意你的腳步，旅人唷。 本能: 成長茁壯
長出新芽攻擊粗心大意的目標閃現犬 (Blink Dog)集團, 小型, 魔法, 組織啃咬 (d8 傷害), 6 HP, 4 護甲
近身
特性: 幻象
你剛才看見牠，現在就不見了。這些獵犬曾經被一名巫師領主擁有，並被灌注了某種幻術魔法構成的偽裝。牠們逃進了他領地周遭的森林，並與那做森林內的狼群和野犬繁衍後代。如果你夠幸運，你也許能透過牠們那閃閃發亮的銀色毛皮以及那怪異的嚎叫聲來找到牠們。牠們擁有一種非凡天賦，讓牠們可以不完全處在牠們看起來所在的位置，並利用這種天賦來擊倒那些遠比牠們強大的獵物。如果你發現自己必須面對一群閃現犬，不妨閉上眼睛與牠們交戰。在不被自然視覺所背叛的情況下，戰鬥可能會更輕鬆一些。正是因為這種邪佞巫術，這個世界的自然環境正逐漸被不自然的產物給玷汙。 本能: 狩獵
讓自己看起來像是位於牠們不存在的位置假象召喚犬群以驚人的速度移動半人馬 (Centaur)成群, 大型, 組織, 聰穎弓 (d6+2 傷害, 1 穿透), 11 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 及遠, Near
特性: 半人半馬</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>德魯伊</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/druid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/druid/</guid>
      <description>德魯伊環視火堆周圍，這些人滿是城市的塵埃與汗味，是什麼將你帶到這些人身邊？或許是慈愛吧──你是否如同母熊照看她的幼崽保護著他們？他們現在是你這群的嗎？你可真有群奇怪的兄弟姊妹。不管你有怎樣的靈感，沒有你銳利的感官和更銳利的獠爪，他們註定不會成功。
你屬於神聖之所；你出生於母土，你的身上戴著她的靈魂之印。你可能也曾有過凡人的生活，或許你也像他們曾居於都城，如今卻已非如此。你拋棄了停滯的定型。聆聽你盟友對他們所雕神像的祈禱，聆聽他們的宗教寓言故事，講述他們將在早已被你拋棄的破爛小鎮中找回的榮耀。
他們的諸神只是年幼的孩童，他們的鋼鐵只是虛假的保護。你走在古老的路上，披大地為衣。你會拿取屬於你的財寶，但你是否會走上與他們相同的路呢？只有時間知道。
名稱 (Names)Elf: Hycorax, Ethanwe, Sinathel, Demanor, Menoliir, Mithralan, Taeros, Aegor
Halfling: Tanner, Dunstan, Rose, Ivy, Robard, Mab, Thistle, Puck, Anne, Serah
Human: Elana, Obelis, Herran, Syla, Andanna, Siobhan, Aziz, Pelin, Sibel, Nils, Wei
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Wise Eyes, Wild Eyes, or Haunting Eyes
Furry Hood, Messy Hair, or Braided Hair
Ceremonial Garb, Practical Leathers, or Weathered Hides
屬性數值 (Stats)Your maximum HP is 6+Constitution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>戰士</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/fighter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/fighter/</guid>
      <description>戰士這是份爛差事－－日復一日靠著你的盔甲和手上技巧討生活，不顧一切地跳入危險之中。當你在巴爾斯伯格的酒吧為他們兩肋插刀時，沒有人為你吹奏黃金號角。當你將還在尖叫的他們從瘋狂深淵的邊緣拽出時，沒有成群天使為你合唱。什麼都沒有。
忘了他們吧。
你這麼做是為了膽識與榮耀，是為了戰鬥的呼嘯、以及那熾熱的鮮血。你是鐵打的猛獸。你的朋友或許帶著鋼鑄的鋒刃，然而，戰士，你本身就是鋼鐵。當你的旅伴在荒野營火旁抱怨著他們的傷口，你則驕傲的背起自己的傷疤。
你即是銅牆鐵壁－－任憑所有撲向你的危險灰飛煙滅。最終，你會是站到最後的那一個。
名稱 (Names)Dwarf: Ozruk, Surtur, Brunhilda, Annika, Janos, Greta, Dim, Rundrig, Jarl, Xotoq
Elf: Elohiir, Sharaseth, Hasrith, Shevaral, Cadeus, Eldar, Kithracet, Thelian
Halfling: Finnegan, Olive, Randolph, Bartleby, Aubrey, Baldwin, Becca
Human: Hawke, Rudiger, Gregor, Brianne, Walton, Castor, Shanna, Ajax, Hob
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Hard Eyes, Dead Eyes, or Eager Eyes
Wild Hair, Shorn Hair, or Battered Helm
Calloused Skin, Tanned Skin, or Scarred Skin</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>法師法術</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/wizard/spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/wizard/spells/</guid>
      <description>法師法術戲法You prepare all of your cantrips every time you prepare spells without having to select them or count them toward your allotment of spells.
LightCantripAn item you touch glows with arcane light, about as bright as a torch. It gives off no heat or sound and requires no fuel, but it is otherwise like a mundane torch. You have complete control of the color of the flame. The spell lasts as long as it is in your presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>洞穴居族</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</guid>
      <description>洞穴居族掘地蟲 (Ankheg)集團, 大型啃咬 (d8+1 傷害), 10 HP, 3 護甲
近身, 及遠
特性: 掘地
彷彿金屬板甲的厚皮和能碾碎一切的強力下顎就很糟糕了，而能將石牆腐蝕出孔洞的滿腹強酸更讓一切雪上加霜。如果牠們的大小和昆蟲相當，情況就已經夠壞的了，但這些該死玩意兒竟然還有膽子長的跟馬一樣長。這絕對不是自然產物！往好處想，還好牠們傾向待在同個地方……？哇，你說的可容易──這些掘地蟲又不是住在你家玉米田底下。 本能: 挖掘坑道
在地底下挖掘坑道從地下猛然鑽出向前方噴吐強酸，腐蝕金屬和血肉穴鼠	(Cave Rat)成群, 小型嚙咬 (d6 傷害, 1 穿透), 7 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 毀亂
有誰沒看過老鼠嗎？牠們就像那樣，只不過又髒又大，而且再也不會怕你了。也許牠們跟你在韃邏的骯髒酒館中用陷阱捉到、用小刀殺死的小傢伙們是親戚，而也許牠們也正在伺機展開那小小的鼠式復仇。 本能: 吞噬
蜂擁而上將某物（或某人）撕成碎片鎖喉怪 (Choker)單獨, 隱匿, 聰穎鎖喉 (d10 傷害), 15 HP, 2 護甲
近身, 及遠
特性: 柔韌彈性
有人說這些鬼東西是一名殘忍巫師的家族後裔，他們因為他而被迫居住在地底。傳說他可怕的實驗使他變得畏懼陽光，而隨著數個世紀過去，他也拖著他的族裔們一起墮落成了不死之軀。這些怪物在某種程度上與人類相似，有著一顆頭、四肢什麼的，只不過牠們的皮膚濕滑而柔韌，雙臂瘦長，指爪緊攫。正如人們所預料的那樣，牠們憎恨所有沾染著陽光臭味的生物。這長期灌輸的嫉妒，可沒那麼容易甩掉。 本能: 拒絕亮光
緊緊擒抱某人，扭絞止住他們的呼吸。拋扔一個被擒抱住的生物斗篷偽怪 (Cloaker)單獨, 隱匿絞纏 (d10 傷害, 無視護甲), 12 HP, 1 護甲</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>牧師</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/cleric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/cleric/</guid>
      <description>牧師地城世界的大地就是個被神遺棄的爛攤子。在安全與被祝福的文明之間，佈滿了走動的死屍、各種的野獸、跟廣袤的超自然之地。那是個神不存在的世界，而這也正是為何需要你的原因。
將神之榮光帶給異教徒不只是你的本性──更是你的使命。你持著劍、槌和咒法宣教，劈開粗野的愚蠢之心，植入神聖之籽。有人說，最好讓神常伴你心。你知道那都是狗屁。神只住在刀鋒之上。
向這個世界證明，誰才是它的主宰。
名稱 (Names)Dwarf: Durga, Aelfar, Gerda, Rurgosh, Bjorn, Drummond, Helga, Siggrun, Freya
Human: Wesley, Brinton, Jon, Sara, Hawthorn, Elise, Clarke, Lenore, Piotr, Dahlia, Carmine
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Kind Eyes, Sharp Eyes, or Sad EyesTonsure, Strange Hair, or BaldFlowing Robes, Habit, or Common GarbThin Body, Knobby Body, or Flabby Body屬性數值 (Stats)Your maximum HP is 8+Constitution.
Your base damage is d6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>牧師法術</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/cleric/spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/cleric/spells/</guid>
      <description>牧師法術禱念Every time you commune, you gain access to all of your rotes without having to select them or count them toward your allotment of spells.
光亮術 (Light)禱念An item you touch glows with divine light, about as bright as a torch. It gives off no heat or sound and requires no fuel but is otherwise like a mundane torch. You have complete control of the color of the flame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>王國住民</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</guid>
      <description>王國住民侍僧 (Acolyte)「他們說，不是每個人都能當大祭司。他們說，不是每個人都能住在白色尖頂。去擦洗地板，他們告訴我，冥界至高神可不會希望看到骯髒的地板，喔是嗎？他們還說這裡將有啟蒙與魔法。呵，這裡只有瘀青的膝蓋和洗碗的雙手。唉，要是我是個牧師就好了。」 本能: 忠實地服侍
遵循教條為凡人的行為提供永恆的獎賞冒險者 (Adventurer)成群, 聰穎利劍 (d6 傷害), 3 HP, 1 護甲
近身
特性: 無盡的熱忱
「地球上的渣滓，他們就是這種人。一群大搖大擺走進城鎮的武裝男女，揮舞炫耀著那總之能把這整個地方夷為平地的魔法和凡俗力量。他們那一袋又一袋的戰利品，還滴著那為此被他們所殺的可憐混蛋的鮮血。如果你問我的話，我會說一場經濟浩劫很快就要發生，整個經濟體系都將被連根拔起。這群危險，捉摸不定的要命流浪漢……噢，等等，你是個冒險者？那當我沒說。」 本能: 不冒險，毋寧死
做一些徒勞的差事衝動行事分享過往輝煌的故事強盜 (Bandit)成群, 聰穎, 組織短劍 (d6 傷害), 3 HP, 1 護甲
近身
絕望，就是劫徒盜匪們的口號。當世道艱辛，除了拾起武器與一群骯髒粗鄙的男男女女一同上路之外，又能怎麼辦呢？儘管攔路搶劫、竊盜、欺詐、行騙和謀殺是如此罪大惡極，但我們都要討口飯吃，又有誰能怪罪他們的？不過話說回來，邪惡也確實存在某些人心中，而誰又能說絕望不是滿足某人低賤慾望所必須的呢？無論如何－－有時是因為這樣，有時則只是因為挨餓。 本能: 搶劫
偷竊某物索要貢品強盜王 (Bandit King)單獨, 聰穎, 組織愛刀 (b[2d10] 傷害), 12 HP, 1 護甲
近身
寧在地獄為王，不在天堂稱臣。 本能: 領導
發號施令敲詐推翻政權弄臣 (Fool)在眾臣中就只有這麼一個人被允許在王宮中說出真話：一切真實、直接而誠實的真相。弄臣將這一切藉著鈴鐺、歡躍騰跳、以及粉白妝容表達了出來，而除他之外又有誰能夠告訴國王孰是孰非？你可以信任弄臣，他們這麼說，尤其是當他把你搞得面紅耳赤，而你情願把他淹死在糞坑的時候。 本能: 嘲弄</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>簡介</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/introduction/</guid>
      <description>簡介地城世界 (Dungeon World)地城世界是奇幻冒險的世界。是個充斥著魔法、神魔、善惡、律法與混沌的世界。勇敢的英雄闖蕩於大地上最危險的角落，追求財富與榮耀。
在地城世界中有形形色色的冒險者。精靈、人類、矮人與半身人都有屬於自己的英雄。他們之中有身穿鐵甲，無人能敵的戰場猛獸；有的則神秘莫測，呼喚並驅使著魔法的力量。這些尋求財寶與榮耀的，有神聖的牧師、有奸巧的盜賊、有強大的聖武士、還有更多更多。
然而，冒險並不只有輕鬆的英雄主義與高尚的英勇行徑。每當遊俠帶著他的朋友穿越古老森林時，數以百計的危險虎視眈眈地等著咬掉他的頭顱。或許，等待著他們的是流著口水的哥布林部隊，又或許，他們行經的是居住著灰衣女巫的詛咒之森？亦或者，一整群怨靈正飢渴地尋找著用以還魂的肉身屍體。可怕嗎？當然，但是財寶也在那裏。在危險深處，無數被世人遺忘的黃金珠寶和魔法散落在你所熟悉世界的陰暗夾縫之間。除了堅定勇敢的英雄們之外，又有誰能夠取回它們？
你和你的朋友就是那些英雄。你們踏足他人無法或不願涉足的險地。怪誕之物潛居於這個世界──你準備好面對牠們了嗎？
吟遊詩人 (The Bard)冒險者之詩乃是不斷向前之路，是錢幣與戰鬥的榮光。在那些鄉農滿座的酒館中被傳唱的故事，總有些許真實，對吧？那些鼓舞農民與國親的歌謠──那些撫慰野獸或讓人瘋狂的歌謠──必定其來有自。
當個詩人吧。來，帶著你的巧舌與機智。你說故事，你唱歌謠。一名尋常樂手只會複誦，而真正的吟遊詩人活在其中。繫上你的靴子吧，高貴的演說家。磨利那把小刀，接受呼喚。總得有人要與那些暴徒、惡棍與即將成為英雄的人們並肩作戰。又有誰比你更能傳誦自己的英雄故事？
沒有別人了。來吧。
牧師 (The Cleric)地城世界的大地就是個被神遺棄的爛攤子。在安全與被祝福的文明之間，佈滿了走動的死屍、各種的野獸、跟廣袤的超自然之地。那是個神不存在的世界，而這也正是為何需要你的原因。
將神之榮光帶給異教徒不只是你的本性──更是你的使命。你持著劍、槌和咒法宣教，劈開粗野的愚蠢之心，植入神聖之籽。有人說，最好讓神常伴你心。你知道那都是狗屁。神只住在刀鋒之上。
向這個世界證明，誰才是它的主宰。
德魯伊 (The Druid)環視火堆周圍，這些人滿是城市的塵埃與汗味，是什麼將你帶到這些人身邊？或許是慈愛吧──你是否如同母熊照看她的幼崽保護著他們？他們現在是你這群的嗎？你可真有群奇怪的兄弟姊妹。不管你有怎樣的靈感，沒有你銳利的感官和更銳利的獠爪，他們註定不會成功。
你屬於神聖之所；你出生於母土，你的身上戴著她的靈魂之印。你可能也曾有過凡人的生活，或許你也像他們曾居於都城，如今卻已非如此。你拋棄了停滯的定型。聆聽你盟友對他們所雕神像的祈禱，聆聽他們的宗教寓言故事，講述他們將在早已被你拋棄的破爛小鎮中找回的榮耀。
他們的諸神只是年幼的孩童，他們的鋼鐵只是虛假的保護。你走在古老的路上，披大地為衣。你會拿取屬於你的財寶，但你是否會走上與他們相同的路呢？只有時間知道。
戰士 (The Fighter)這是份爛差事－－日復一日靠著你的盔甲和手上技巧討生活，不顧一切地跳入危險之中。當你在巴爾斯伯格的酒吧為他們兩肋插刀時，沒有人為你吹奏黃金號角。當你將還在尖叫的他們從瘋狂深淵的邊緣拽出時，沒有成群天使為你合唱。什麼都沒有。忘了他們吧。
你這麼做是為了膽識與榮耀，是為了戰鬥的呼嘯、以及那熾熱的鮮血。你是鐵打的猛獸。你的朋友或許帶著鋼鑄的鋒刃，然而，戰士，你本身就是鋼鐵。當你的旅伴在荒野營火旁抱怨著他們的傷口，你則驕傲的背起自己的傷疤。
你即是銅牆鐵壁－－任憑所有撲向你的危險灰飛煙滅。最終，你會是站到最後的那一個。
聖武士 (The Paladin)地獄正在等候。或寒冰，或烈火，或地城世界中那些該死罪人們所應得的懲罰，構成了此地的永恆折磨。殘虐或者救贖，一切由你。神聖之士，戰爭機器，全善與光明的聖堂武士，是吧？牧師或許在夜裡向天界上蒼祈禱。戰士或許會以「善」之名揮舞利劍。但只有你知道，何謂善。
眾神之眼，之手，之殺戮神罰，這就是你。你所賜的乃是公義與美德－－乃是正義，乃是願景。你胸懷同伴們所欠缺的，純粹之意念。
所以引導這些愚者吧，聖武士。擔負起你的聖潔使命，將救贖帶到這個破爛世界。
敗者毋怨悽慘，對吧？
遊俠 (The Ranger)與你同行的這些都市兒童。他們可曾聽見孤狼的吠叫？可曾感受過東方荒蕪沙漠的狂風呼嘯？可曾如你那樣以弓刃狩獵？當然他媽的沒有。那就是為什麼他們需要你。
嚮導、獵手、荒野的造物。你遠遠不只如此。你在荒野中一向孤獨，但那偉大之物的呼喚－－或許可以稱之為命運－－將你與這些都市人的命連繫在了一起。他們或許勇敢。或許強大健壯。但只有你通曉這兩者間的秘密。
沒有你，他們就會迷失。在鮮血與黑暗之中燒出通往前方的道路吧，神行客。
The ThiefYou’ve heard them, sitting around the campfire. Bragging about this battle or that, or about how their gods are smiling on your merry band.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>聖武士</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/paladin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/paladin/</guid>
      <description>聖武士地獄正在等候。或寒冰，或烈火，或地城世界中那些該死罪人們所應得的懲罰，構成了此地的永恆折磨。殘虐或者救贖，一切由你。神聖之士，戰爭機器，全善與光明的聖堂武士，是吧？牧師或許在夜裡向天界上蒼祈禱。戰士或許會以「善」之名揮舞利劍。但只有你知道，何謂善。
眾神之眼，之手，之殺戮神罰，這就是你。你所賜的乃是公義與美德－－乃是正義，乃是願景。你胸懷同伴們所欠缺的，純粹之意念。
所以引導這些愚者吧，聖武士。擔負起你的聖潔使命，將救贖帶到這個破爛世界。
敗者毋怨悽慘，對吧？
名稱 (Names)Thaddeus, Augustine, Lux, Cassius, Hadrian, Lucia, Octavia, Regulus, Valeria, Sanguinus, Titanius
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Kind Eyes, Fiery Eyes, or Glowing Eyes
Helmet, Styled Hair, or Bald
Worn Holy Symbol or Fancy Holy Symbol
Fit Body, Bulky Body, or Thin Body
屬性數值 (Stats)Your maximum HP is 10+Constitution.
Your base damage is d10.
起始動作 (Starting Moves)You are human, so you get this move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>裝備</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/equipment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/equipment/</guid>
      <description>裝備在腐朽的墳墓與被世界遺忘的財寶堆中堆滿了許許多多有用的物品。戰士可以在其中找到一把嶄新的鋒利寶劍、而盜賊也許能從中偶然找到一瓶致命毒藥。大部分的物品都是尋常無奇──沒有魔法、也沒什麼真正獨特的特質。對於遊戲機制的動作來說，任何帶有魔法或獨樹一格的物品都會被視作凡物。此外，戰士的招牌武器也永遠不會被視作凡物。
每件裝備都會帶有複數個標籤。這些標籤將告訴你這件裝備會如何影響使用它的角色（像是 +護甲值），或暗示它該如何被使用（例如範圍標籤）。就如同《地城世界》中的其他事物，它們能夠引導你在遊戲中創造故事情節。比如說，如果一把武器帶有「不便」標籤，那麼這可能意味著當你在劈砍檢定中失敗時，這把武器會有很大的機會脫手，落到地面。
以下列出的絕非詳盡完整的清單──自由地創造你自己的標籤吧。
泛用裝備標籤這些泛用標籤可以適用於幾乎任何裝備。你會在防具、武器、和一般冒險工具上看到它們。
內服 (Applied): 它只有在你確切地讓目標服用、或混進他們嚥下的飲食內才會生效。
不便 (Awkward): 它相當笨重且難以使用。
+修正 (+Bonus): 它將改變你在特定情況下的行動成效。比如說「憶述見聞下次+1」或是「砍劈持續-1」等等。
n 金幣 (n coins): 它在正常情況下值多少錢。如果價格包括「－魅力」的文字，則將其價格減去購買者的魅力值（而非修正值）。
危險 (Dangerous): 使用它很容易讓你惹上麻煩。如果你與它互動時沒有準備適當的預防措施，則GM可以自由地描述你愚蠢行動的後果。
食物 (Ration): 它是可食用的，或多或少。
限定 (Requires): 它只對某些人有用。如果你無法滿足它的條件，則它的效果會減弱，或甚至完全無效。
緩慢 (Slow): 使用它需要花費數分鐘或更久的時間。
接觸 (Touch): 它需要透過直接接觸到目標肌膚的方式來被使用。
雙手 (Two-handed): 它需要兩隻手才能被有效地使用。
n 重量 (n weight): 計算列有重量的物品的總重，並與你的負載量相比較。未列有重量的東西不能被隨身攜帶。100枚標準面額的金幣為1 重量。有著相同價值的寶石或美術品可能會更輕或更重。
穿戴 (Worn): 你必須要穿戴它才能夠使用它。
n 使用次數 (n Uses): 它只能被使用 n 次。 武器 (Weapons)殺死怪物的並非武器，而是揮舞它們的人。這也是為什麼《地城世界》中的武器並沒有列出其傷害數據。武器的主要重點在於其標籤，用來描述這把武器的用途與特性。一把匕首的重點並不在於它能造成比其他刀劍更多或更少的傷害，而在於它的小巧靈活，且能輕易地在極近距離下重創對手。因此，法師手中匕首的威脅性，就很明顯不如技巧純熟的戰士手上的那把匕首。
武器標籤武器可能會帶有一些主要用以幫助你描述它們的標籤（例如「生鏽」或「閃閃發光」），但以下這些標籤除了描述的用途之外，還有著其他遊戲機制上的效果。
n 彈藥 (n Ammo): 它被視作適當遠程武器的彈藥。數字ｎ並不代表確切的箭矢或投石數量，而是代表你手頭上還剩下什麼。
強力 (Forceful): 它可以迫使某人後退幾步，或甚至讓他們失足倒地。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>角色創造</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/character_creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/character_creation/</guid>
      <description>角色創造Making Dungeon World characters is quick and easy. You should all create your first characters together at the beginning of your first session. Character creation is, just like play, a kind of conversation—everyone should be there for it.
You may need to make another character during play, if yours gets killed for example. If so, no worries, the character creation process helps you make a new character that fits into the group in just a few minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>遊俠</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/ranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/classes/ranger/</guid>
      <description>遊俠與你同行的這些都市兒童。他們可曾聽見孤狼的吠叫？可曾感受過東方荒蕪沙漠的狂風呼嘯？可曾如你那樣以弓刃狩獵？當然他媽的沒有。那就是為什麼他們需要你。
嚮導、獵手、荒野的造物。你遠遠不只如此。你在荒野中一向孤獨，但那偉大之物的呼喚－－或許可以稱之為命運－－將你與這些都市人的命連繫在了一起。他們或許勇敢。或許強大健壯。但只有你通曉這兩者間的秘密。
沒有你，他們就會迷失。在鮮血與黑暗之中燒出通往前方的道路吧，神行客。
名稱 (Names)Elf: Throndir, Elrosine, Aranwe, Celion, Dambrath, Lanethe
Human: Jonah, Halek, Brandon, Emory, Shrike, Nora, Diana
外觀 (Look)從每列中各自選擇一項：
Wild Eyes, Sharp Eyes, or Animal Eyes
Hooded Head, Wild Hair, or Bald
Cape, Camouflage, or Traveling Clothes
Lithe Body, Wild Body, or Sharp Body
屬性數值 (Stats)Your maximum HP is 8+Constitution.
Your base damage is d8.
起始動作 (Starting Moves)Choose a race and gain the corresponding move:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>遊玩範例</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/example/</guid>
      <description>遊玩範例我正在主持一場遊戲，我的玩家有艾薩克（扮演歐瑪爾(Omar)）、班（扮演布莉安娜(Brianne)）、艾米（扮演諾拉(Nora)）、和丹（扮演拉瑟(Rath)）。團隊們來到了一個哥布林部落，這些哥布林們正在準備進行儀式，獻祭一條罕見而珍貴的白化鱷魚（在這座城市的富人中被當作寵物）。
三名哥布林戰士──吸食了致幻氣體──尖聲怪叫的朝著布莉安娜發起衝鋒。另外兩名則躲到掩體後，備好牠們的弓箭，並急切地向拉瑟比出手勢以抵禦他配戴的邪眼。還有一群三人小隊潛進了房間外緣的陰影之中，準備偷襲。哥布林大祭司和她的助手仍繼續進行著儀式，揉著鱷魚翻出的肚皮來讓牠保持順從，並拿出祭祀刀準備割開牠的喉嚨。
當我描述完整個情境後，我給他們一個展開行動的機會，以確保遊戲是透過對話進行：「那麼，你們打算做什麼？」
艾薩克最先展開了行動：「這個房間的外緣有足夠我躲藏的陰影嗎？」「有的。」我說：「很顯然，哥布林們並不怎麼喜歡光線。這個房間的外緣區域消失在了黑暗中，只有搖搖欲墜的牆壁和滿地碎石隱約可見。」「太好了！我要到那邊去，往那些鬼鬼祟祟的傢伙去的那邊。歐瑪爾回頭看了一眼，戴上兜帽，並遁入了陰影之中。我打算待會從這裡的陰影……照亮著儀式祭壇的火炬這邊跳出來。」
我看了看地圖，然後說：「嗯，我想你顯然會需要面對被發現的危險。在我看來這應該會使用到敏捷，畢竟你需要謹慎且安靜的移動。」於是他拿起了骰子並擲骰。骰子擲出了 1 跟 2，加上他的敏捷加值為 2，總共只有 5。「該死！」他抱怨道。
我對於該怎麼做已經有了一些想法，但我還是對照了我的動作清單做確認。果然，我打算讓他的腳卡進碎石堆中的主意符合其中一個動作，也就是讓某人陷入窘境。於是我說道：「隨著你在陰影中前進，你的腳踩上了碎石堆，碎石鬆動，反過來壓住了你的腳，你動彈不得。更糟的是，這些滾動的碎石喚醒了陰影中的某個存在，你聽到了一聲深沉沙啞的呼吸聲。你會想大喊求助但暴露自己的位置，還是嘗試自己掙脫？」
「呃……我不確定。」
「沒關係，我們晚點再來問你。其他人，你們打算做什麼？」
丹起身。「那些哥布林躲進了陰影對吧？我能看見牠們嗎？」「乍看之下無法，你想把牠們找出來嗎？」「沒，我只是想知道牠們能不能做為我睡眠術的目標。我要驅動魔法之風，將其化作一道在整個房間內吹拂的沉靜夏日微風。」
丹為他的施放法術動作擲骰以施放睡眠術。他的兩顆骰子總和為 6，加上他的+2 智力，總共為 8。他必須做出選擇。「你能夠感覺到法術從你手中釋放出去，這道魔法之風籠罩了哥布林的獻祭儀式。這個動作提供了一些選項，你打算選擇哪一個來維持這個法術？」
丹思考著他的選項。「我之後可能會需要讓更多的傢伙陷入沉睡。布莉安娜，妳能夠在我遇到麻煩時掩護我嗎？還是我應該選擇下次-1？」
「當然，我可以掩護你。」班說道。
「OK，那我要選擇遭遇危險的選項。」
「好極了。」我說道：「那些哥布林戰士吸食了致幻氣體對吧？藥效調諧了牠們的感官：他們能夠微微感覺到那股魔法之風的存在，因此牠們現在全都衝向了你，而不是布莉安娜。你讓多少生物陷入了睡眠呢？」
丹擲骰。「看起來只有一隻，該死。」
「在哥布林們長時間的祈禱途中，大祭司因為你的魔法而倒在了地上。她的助手立刻開始搖晃她，將她叫醒。牠們都把注意力從白化鱷魚身上移開，而因為沒有人在揉摸牠的肚皮，白化鱷魚也不再滿足。不過在此同時，那些煙霧繚繞的哥布林戰士們，牠們正氣勢洶洶的向著拉瑟而來。」
班加入了進來。「我佔到拉瑟和那群瘋狂哥布林們之間，讓自己成為一個顯眼的大目標，用一聲大喊吸引哥布林們的注意。」
「這聽起來像是個保衛動作。」我說道。
「沒問題，我骰出了 7，所以我獲得 1 掌握。」
「很好。這三隻冒煙的哥布林朝著拉瑟猛衝過去，瘋狂地揮舞著牠們的匕首。」
「不，牠們別想！」班說道：「我花費我的掌握，擋在牠們面前，並讓攻擊全部轉移到我身上。」
「所以布莉安娜在最後一刻挺身介入，把拉瑟推開，改為讓哥布林撲到她身上。這看起來是 5 點傷害。諾拉，布莉安娜把這三個精神錯亂的哥布林控制在她身邊，拉瑟才剛讓女祭司陷入沉睡，鱷魚開始躁動，歐瑪爾則不見蹤影……你打算做什麼？」
「首先我搭箭射向其中一名哥布林弓箭手，在我這麼做的同時，我微微點頭示意，讓坎托一頭躍進陰影之中。牠受過狩獵的訓練，我要牠尋找歐瑪爾以確保他平安無事。」
在回答之前，我檢查了一下遊俠的命令動作，確保我明白坎托的搜尋會有什麼效果。「好吧，坎托大概很快就能自己找到歐瑪爾。如果妳跟牠一起潛進黑暗中，那妳為了找尋歐瑪爾所進行的審視現狀的擲骰將會得到牠給妳的加值。不過，聽起來妳打算先進行瞄準射擊？」
「噢，哥布林弓箭手算被我偷襲嗎？我以為這只會是個射擊動作。」艾米答道。
是時候換我做出決定了。「不，牠們把注意力完全放到了拉瑟身上，牠們馬上就要射出箭矢。我認為妳的行動符合偷襲的條件，因為牠們實在太專注了。」
「太棒了！那我繼續，並射向離我最近的哥布林的手臂，我要讓牠失手落下牠的弓。這應該是+敏捷……10！牠放開了牠的弓並受到 4 點傷害。」
我先確認了一下哥布林的數據，接著回答：「是的，這一箭會殺死牠。而且因為妳射穿了牠的手臂，所以牠完全沒機會射擊。然而，另一名弓箭手還是朝著拉瑟射出飛箭，造成 2 點傷害。拉瑟，布莉安娜將你推到了一旁，你本來以為自己安全了，但在那一剎那，一支箭射中了你的腿，你打算怎麼辦？……事實上，先等一下，我們來看看歐瑪爾做了什麼。」
艾薩克現在已經把事情好好想清楚了。「那個深沉沙啞的呼吸聲，我可以分辨出它是從哪裡傳來的嗎？它是像人類體型會發出的刺耳聲音、還是怪物尺寸的刺耳聲音？」
「聽起來你打算試著藉由仔細傾聽來獲得一些情報，是吧？」我希望這麼說能提醒艾薩克有個動作能做到這件事，而不是直接要他進行動作。
「喔對！所以我要審視現狀，盡我可能的保持靜默，試著捕捉任何細節以搞清楚這是什麼東西。加上我的睿知修正之後的結果是 7，呼。我應該要注意些什麼呢？」
我花了點時間看了看我的筆記和地圖，確保我給了他所有的情報。「嗯，事實上，那的確不是哥布林。那些哥布林牠們略過了你，來到比你更靠近光亮的地方，準備在你朋友們的背後捅一刀，但卻沒有注意到你。而你所看見的，是一隻巨型鱷魚的吻部尖端頂在碎石堆上，那刺耳的聲音就是來自於牠。看樣子那頭白化鱷魚有個塊頭特別大的家人呢，牠的體型跟馬一樣大。如果你想要搬動石頭以從中掙脫，那牠幾乎肯定會聽見你的舉動。你打算怎麼辦呢？」
艾薩克沉思一會。「所以，我可以嘗試掙脫離開，但很有可能會面對發出聲音的危險。或者……我撕下斗篷的一角，並將它浸泡在我一整劑的黃金根毒藥裡。這是種需要服用後才能生效的毒藥，但如果我能在這頭巨大鱷魚吞下我之前，讓牠吞下這片布料，牠就會把我當成是一名可信賴的盟友，然後我就能利用牠去對付那些哥布林。」
「沒問題！」這聽起來是個高風險的計畫，但並沒有瘋狂到無法執行。然而也是時候切換到其他人的場景了。「所以，歐瑪爾將斗篷的碎片浸泡在毒藥中，布莉安娜正被三隻吸嗨了的哥布林砍抓，諾拉留神注意著歐瑪爾的情況，有幾隻哥布林們潛匿在陰影中，一隻哥布林弓箭手站在祭壇旁，白化鱷魚醒轉起身，而拉瑟的膝蓋剛中了一箭。呼，拉瑟，你打算為這支箭做些什麼？」</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>