<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsters on 地城世界 HTML SRD</title>
    <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monsters on 地城世界 HTML SRD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cavern Dwellers</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</guid>
      <description>Cavern Dwellers掘地蟲	Group, LargeBite (d8+1 damage), 10 HP, 3 Armor
Close, Reach
Special Qualities: Burrowing
A hide like plate armor and great crushing mandibles are problematic. A stomach full of acid that can burn a hole through a stone wall makes them all the worse. They’d be bad enough if they were proper insect-sized, but these things have the gall to be as long as any given horse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Woods</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</guid>
      <description>Dark WoodsAssassin Vine	Solitary, Stealthy, AmorphousThorns (d10 damage, 1 piercing), 15 HP, 1 Armor
Close, Reach, Messy
Special Qualities: Plant
Among the animals there exists a clear division ‘tween hunter and hunted. All it takes is a glance to know—by fangs and glowing eyes or claws or venomous sting—which of the creatures of this world are meant to kill and which stand to be killed. Such a split, if you have the eyes to see it, cuts the world of leaves and flowers in twain, as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Folk of the Realm</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</guid>
      <description>Folk of the RealmAcolyte	“Can’t all be the High Priest, they said. Can’t all wield the White Spire, they said. Scrub the floor, they told me. The Cthonic Overgod don’t want a messy floor, do he? They said it’d be enlightenment and magic. Feh. It’s bruised knees and dishpan hands. If only I’d been a cleric, instead.” Instinct: To serve dutifully
Follow dogmaOffer eternal reward for mortal deedsAdventurer	Horde, IntelligentSword (d6 damage), 3 HP, 1 Armor</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower Depths</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</guid>
      <description>Lower DepthsAboleth	Group, Huge, IntelligentTentacle (d10+3 damage), 18 HP, 0 Armor
Reach
Special Qualities: Telepathy
Deep below the surface of the world, in freshwater seas untouched by the sun, dwell the aboleth. Fish the size of whales, with strange growths of gelatinous feelers used to probe the lightless shores. They’re served by slaves: blind albino victims of any race unfortunate enough to stumble on them, drained of thought and life by the powers of the aboleth’s alien mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monsters</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</guid>
      <description>MonstersGreat heroes need horrendous antagonists. This section is about how to create and play as those antagonists—from the lowly goblin warrior to the hellish demon.
Using MonstersA monster is any living (or undead) thing that stands in the characters’ way.
How you use these monsters follows directly from your agenda and principles. Stay true to your principles, use your moves and pursue your agenda—you can’t go wrong. Your first agenda is to portray a fantastic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planar Powers</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</guid>
      <description>Planar PowersAngel	Solitary, Terrifying, Divine, Intelligent, OrganizedSword of Flames (b[2d10]+4 damage, ignores armor), 18 HP, 4 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Wings
“So was it written that the heavens opened up to Avra’hal and did an angel from the clouds emerge to speak unto her and so did it appear to her as her firstborn daughter—beautiful, of ebon skin and golden eyes—and did Avra’hal weep to see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravenous Hordes</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</guid>
      <description>Ravenous HordesFormian Drone	Horde, Organized, CautiousBite (d6 damage), 7 HP, 4 Armor
Close
Special Qualities: Hive connection, Insectoid
With good cause, they say that these creatures (like all insects, really) are claimed by the powers of Law. They are order made flesh—a perfectly stratified society in which every larva, hatchling and adult knows its place in the great hive. The formian is some strange intersection of men and ants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Denizens</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</guid>
      <description>Swamp DenizensBakunawa	Solitary, Large, Intelligent, Messy, ForcefulBite (d10+3 damage, 1 piercing), 16 HP, 2 Armor
Close, Reach
Special Qualities: Amphibious
Dragon-Turtle’s sister is a mighty serpent queen. Ten yards of scales and muscle, they say she wakes with a hunger when the sun disappears from the sky. She is attracted by bright light in the darkness and like any snake, the Bakunawa is sneaky. She will seek first to beguile and mislead and will only strike out with violence when no other option is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Experiments</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</guid>
      <description>Twisted ExperimentsBulette	Solitary, Huge, ConstructBite (d10+5 damage, 3 piercing), 20 HP, 3 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Burrowing
A seasoned caravan guard learns to listen for the calls of a scout or sentry with a keen ear. A few extra seconds after the alarm is raised can mean life or death. Different cries mean different responses, too—a call of “orcs!” means draw your sword and steady for blood but a call of “bandits!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undead Legions</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</guid>
      <description>Undead LegionsAbomination	Solitary, Large, Construct, TerrifyingSlam (d10+3 damage), 20 HP, 1 Armor
Close, Reach, Forceful
Special Qualities: Many limbs, heads, and so on
Corpses sewn onto corpses make up the bulk of these shambling masses of dark magic. Most undead are crafted to be controlled—made to serve some purpose like building a tower or serving as guardians. Not so the abomination. The last aspect of the ritual used to grant fire to their hellish limbs invokes a hatred so severe that the abomination knows but one task: to tear and rend at the very thing it cannot have—life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>