<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monsters on 地城世界 HTML SRD</title>
    <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monsters on 地城世界 HTML SRD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Lower Depths</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/depths/</guid>
      <description>Lower DepthsAboleth	Group, Huge, IntelligentTentacle (d10+3 damage), 18 HP, 0 Armor
Reach
Special Qualities: Telepathy
Deep below the surface of the world, in freshwater seas untouched by the sun, dwell the aboleth. Fish the size of whales, with strange growths of gelatinous feelers used to probe the lightless shores. They’re served by slaves: blind albino victims of any race unfortunate enough to stumble on them, drained of thought and life by the powers of the aboleth’s alien mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monsters</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/overview/</guid>
      <description>MonstersGreat heroes need horrendous antagonists. This section is about how to create and play as those antagonists—from the lowly goblin warrior to the hellish demon.
Using MonstersA monster is any living (or undead) thing that stands in the characters’ way.
How you use these monsters follows directly from your agenda and principles. Stay true to your principles, use your moves and pursue your agenda—you can’t go wrong. Your first agenda is to portray a fantastic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Planar Powers</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/planes/</guid>
      <description>Planar PowersAngel	Solitary, Terrifying, Divine, Intelligent, OrganizedSword of Flames (b[2d10]+4 damage, ignores armor), 18 HP, 4 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Wings
“So was it written that the heavens opened up to Avra’hal and did an angel from the clouds emerge to speak unto her and so did it appear to her as her firstborn daughter—beautiful, of ebon skin and golden eyes—and did Avra’hal weep to see it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ravenous Hordes</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/hordes/</guid>
      <description>Ravenous HordesFormian Drone	Horde, Organized, CautiousBite (d6 damage), 7 HP, 4 Armor
Close
Special Qualities: Hive connection, Insectoid
With good cause, they say that these creatures (like all insects, really) are claimed by the powers of Law. They are order made flesh—a perfectly stratified society in which every larva, hatchling and adult knows its place in the great hive. The formian is some strange intersection of men and ants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swamp Denizens</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/swamp/</guid>
      <description>Swamp DenizensBakunawa	Solitary, Large, Intelligent, Messy, ForcefulBite (d10+3 damage, 1 piercing), 16 HP, 2 Armor
Close, Reach
Special Qualities: Amphibious
Dragon-Turtle’s sister is a mighty serpent queen. Ten yards of scales and muscle, they say she wakes with a hunger when the sun disappears from the sky. She is attracted by bright light in the darkness and like any snake, the Bakunawa is sneaky. She will seek first to beguile and mislead and will only strike out with violence when no other option is available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twisted Experiments</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/experiments/</guid>
      <description>Twisted ExperimentsBulette	Solitary, Huge, ConstructBite (d10+5 damage, 3 piercing), 20 HP, 3 Armor
Close, Forceful
Special Qualities: Burrowing
A seasoned caravan guard learns to listen for the calls of a scout or sentry with a keen ear. A few extra seconds after the alarm is raised can mean life or death. Different cries mean different responses, too—a call of “orcs!” means draw your sword and steady for blood but a call of “bandits!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Undead Legions</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/undead/</guid>
      <description>Undead Legions憎惡屍魔 (Abomination)Solitary, Large, Construct, TerrifyingSlam (d10+3 damage), 20 HP, 1 Armor
Close, Reach, Forceful
Special Qualities: Many limbs, heads, and so on
Corpses sewn onto corpses make up the bulk of these shambling masses of dark magic. Most undead are crafted to be controlled—made to serve some purpose like building a tower or serving as guardians. Not so the abomination. The last aspect of the ritual used to grant fire to their hellish limbs invokes a hatred so severe that the abomination knows but one task: to tear and rend at the very thing it cannot have—life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>幽暗森林</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/woods/</guid>
      <description>幽暗森林殺手藤 (Assassin Vine)單獨, 隱匿, 不定型荊棘 (d10 傷害, 1 穿透), 15 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 及遠, 毀亂
特性: 植物
在動物的世界中，狩獵者與獵物之間存在著明顯的區別。你只需一眼就能看穿－－透過那鋒利尖牙和發光眼瞳、或利爪、或毒刺－－這個世界上的某些生物就是注定要殺戮，而某些則是注定被獵殺。或許你能發現，這類差異也同樣將這個世界上的綠葉鮮花分成了兩半。在森林結社的德魯伊們清楚知曉這件事。遊俠們，也可能會在為時已晚前發現這種植物。然而，那些平民百姓，當他們徘徊在他們不應前往之處－－當他們深入爬藤蔓生的森林深處，忽然，啪噠一聲，這些飢餓的藤索緊緊纏勒，將這些肥美的獵物拖進了灌木叢中。注意你的腳步，旅人唷。 本能: 成長茁壯
長出新芽攻擊粗心大意的目標閃現犬 (Blink Dog)集團, 小型, 魔法, 組織啃咬 (d8 傷害), 6 HP, 4 護甲
近身
特性: 幻象
你剛才看見牠，現在就不見了。這些獵犬曾經被一名巫師領主擁有，並被灌注了某種幻術魔法構成的偽裝。牠們逃進了他領地周遭的森林，並與那做森林內的狼群和野犬繁衍後代。如果你夠幸運，你也許能透過牠們那閃閃發亮的銀色毛皮以及那怪異的嚎叫聲來找到牠們。牠們擁有一種非凡天賦，讓牠們可以不完全處在牠們看起來所在的位置，並利用這種天賦來擊倒那些遠比牠們強大的獵物。如果你發現自己必須面對一群閃現犬，不妨閉上眼睛與牠們交戰。在不被自然視覺所背叛的情況下，戰鬥可能會更輕鬆一些。正是因為這種邪佞巫術，這個世界的自然環境正逐漸被不自然的產物給玷汙。 本能: 狩獵
讓自己看起來像是位於牠們不存在的位置假象召喚犬群以驚人的速度移動半人馬 (Centaur)成群, 大型, 組織, 聰穎弓 (d6+2 傷害, 1 穿透), 11 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 及遠, Near
特性: 半人半馬</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>洞穴居族</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/caverns/</guid>
      <description>洞穴居族掘地蟲 (Ankheg)集團, 大型啃咬 (d8+1 傷害), 10 HP, 3 護甲
近身, 及遠
特性: 掘地
彷彿金屬板甲的厚皮和能碾碎一切的強力下顎就很糟糕了，而能將石牆腐蝕出孔洞的滿腹強酸更讓一切雪上加霜。如果牠們的大小和昆蟲相當，情況就已經夠壞的了，但這些該死玩意兒竟然還有膽子長的跟馬一樣長。這絕對不是自然產物！往好處想，還好牠們傾向待在同個地方……？哇，你說的可容易──這些掘地蟲又不是住在你家玉米田底下。 本能: 挖掘坑道
在地底下挖掘坑道從地下猛然鑽出向前方噴吐強酸，腐蝕金屬和血肉穴鼠	(Cave Rat)成群, 小型嚙咬 (d6 傷害, 1 穿透), 7 HP, 1 護甲
近身, 毀亂
有誰沒看過老鼠嗎？牠們就像那樣，只不過又髒又大，而且再也不會怕你了。也許牠們跟你在韃邏的骯髒酒館中用陷阱捉到、用小刀殺死的小傢伙們是親戚，而也許牠們也正在伺機展開那小小的鼠式復仇。 本能: 吞噬
蜂擁而上將某物（或某人）撕成碎片鎖喉怪 (Choker)單獨, 隱匿, 聰穎鎖喉 (d10 傷害), 15 HP, 2 護甲
近身, 及遠
特性: 柔韌彈性
有人說這些鬼東西是一名殘忍巫師的家族後裔，他們因為他而被迫居住在地底。傳說他可怕的實驗使他變得畏懼陽光，而隨著數個世紀過去，他也拖著他的族裔們一起墮落成了不死之軀。這些怪物在某種程度上與人類相似，有著一顆頭、四肢什麼的，只不過牠們的皮膚濕滑而柔韌，雙臂瘦長，指爪緊攫。正如人們所預料的那樣，牠們憎恨所有沾染著陽光臭味的生物。這長期灌輸的嫉妒，可沒那麼容易甩掉。 本能: 拒絕亮光
緊緊擒抱某人，扭絞止住他們的呼吸。拋扔一個被擒抱住的生物斗篷偽怪 (Cloaker)單獨, 隱匿絞纏 (d10 傷害, 無視護甲), 12 HP, 1 護甲</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>王國住民</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/monsters/folk/</guid>
      <description>王國住民侍僧 (Acolyte)「他們說，不是每個人都能當大祭司。他們說，不是每個人都能住在白色尖頂。去擦洗地板，他們告訴我，冥界至高神可不會希望看到骯髒的地板，喔是嗎？他們還說這裡將有啟蒙與魔法。呵，這裡只有瘀青的膝蓋和洗碗的雙手。唉，要是我是個牧師就好了。」 本能: 忠實地服侍
遵循教條為凡人的行為提供永恆的獎賞冒險者 (Adventurer)成群, 聰穎利劍 (d6 傷害), 3 HP, 1 護甲
近身
特性: 無盡的熱忱
「地球上的渣滓，他們就是這種人。一群大搖大擺走進城鎮的武裝男女，揮舞炫耀著那總之能把這整個地方夷為平地的魔法和凡俗力量。他們那一袋又一袋的戰利品，還滴著那為此被他們所殺的可憐混蛋的鮮血。如果你問我的話，我會說一場經濟浩劫很快就要發生，整個經濟體系都將被連根拔起。這群危險，捉摸不定的要命流浪漢……噢，等等，你是個冒險者？那當我沒說。」 本能: 不冒險，毋寧死
做一些徒勞的差事衝動行事分享過往輝煌的故事強盜 (Bandit)成群, 聰穎, 組織短劍 (d6 傷害), 3 HP, 1 護甲
近身
絕望，就是劫徒盜匪們的口號。當世道艱辛，除了拾起武器與一群骯髒粗鄙的男男女女一同上路之外，又能怎麼辦呢？儘管攔路搶劫、竊盜、欺詐、行騙和謀殺是如此罪大惡極，但我們都要討口飯吃，又有誰能怪罪他們的？不過話說回來，邪惡也確實存在某些人心中，而誰又能說絕望不是滿足某人低賤慾望所必須的呢？無論如何－－有時是因為這樣，有時則只是因為挨餓。 本能: 搶劫
偷竊某物索要貢品強盜王 (Bandit King)單獨, 聰穎, 組織愛刀 (高[2d10] 傷害), 12 HP, 1 護甲
近身
寧在地獄為王，不在天堂稱臣。 本能: 領導
發號施令敲詐推翻政權弄臣 (Fool)在眾臣中就只有這麼一個人被允許在王宮中說出真話：一切真實、直接而誠實的真相。弄臣將這一切藉著鈴鐺、歡躍騰跳、以及粉白妝容表達了出來，而除他之外又有誰能夠告訴國王孰是孰非？你可以信任弄臣，他們這麼說，尤其是當他把你搞得面紅耳赤，而你情願把他淹死在糞坑的時候。 本能: 嘲弄</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>