<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gms on 地城世界 HTML SRD</title>
    <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gms on 地城世界 HTML SRD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Delving</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/advanced_delving/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/advanced_delving/</guid>
      <description>Advanced DelvingDungeon World portrays a specific kind of fantasy adventure—one with elves and dwarves, heroes and villains, and characters struggling for riches and glory in a dangerous world. Maybe you’ve got an idea for something different—maybe your Dungeon World is set on a blasted desert planet, peopled by savage cannibals and ruled by haughty psychics. Or maybe you want to play a game where humans are the only race available, but they belong to clans or families as different from each other as a gnome is from a dwarf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Session</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/first_session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/first_session/</guid>
      <description>First SessionThe first session of a game of Dungeon World begins with character creation. Character creation is also world creation, the details on the character sheets and the questions that you ask establish what Dungeon World is like—who lives in it and what’s going on.
This section is for the GM so it’s addressed to you—the GM. For the players, the first session is just like every other. They just have to play their characters like real people and explore Dungeon World.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fronts</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/fronts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/fronts/</guid>
      <description>FrontsFronts are secret tomes of GM knowledge. Each is a collection of linked dangers—threats to the characters specifically and to the people, places, and things the characters care about. It also includes one or more impending dooms, the horrible things that will happen without the characters’ intervention. “Fronts” comes, of course, from “fighting on two fronts” which is just where you want the characters to be—surrounded by threats, danger and adventure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The world</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/the_world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/the_world/</guid>
      <description>The worldMuch of the adventuring life is spent in dusty, forgotten tombs or in places of terror and life-threatening danger. It’s commonplace to awaken from a short and fitful rest still deep in the belly of the world and surrounded by foes. When the time comes to emerge from these places—whether laden with the spoils of battle or beaten and bloody—an adventurer seeks out safety and solace.
These are the comforts of civilization: a warm bath, a meal of mead and bread, the company of fellow men and elves and dwarves and halflings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>擔任GM</title>
      <link>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://hazmole.github.io/Dungeon-World-HTML-SRD-release/gm/basics/</guid>
      <description>擔任GM奇幻風格有許多種不同的類別，每一種類別對於如何主持遊戲也會有不同的風格和建議。地城世界是專門為其中一種風格而設計的──一個存在著精靈、獸人、龍、和魔法的世界，在這裡，黑暗深沉的危險與輕鬆愉快的冒險彼此交織。本章節中的規則將協助你以這種風格來主持遊戲。
角色們在擲骰和採取行動時需要遵守規則。而做為GM，你也有必須遵守的規則。在遊戲過程中，你將會需要裁決、宣判、並描述這個世界的變化──地城世界為此提供了一個框架來指導你該如何主持遊戲。
本章節的內容並不是提供給GM的建議、也不是關於那些讓你更好遊玩地城世界遊戲的選用技巧和訣竅，而是為任何打算擔當GM位置的人提供應該遵守的程序和規則。
主持地城世界：框架地城世界這個遊戲的運行基礎主要建立於下列幾個要素；GM的目標事項、原則、和動作。目標事項代表著你在遊戲中預計要做到的事情。原則提供一些指引，讓你能專注於完成你的目標事項。GM動作則是那些你在每時每刻用來推動遊戲進行的實際手段。每當玩家擲骰失敗時、規則要求你這麼做時、或是玩家們看著你，等待你描述接下來發生的情況時，就是你使用這些動作的時機。你的動作將維持敘事的連貫性，並推進遊戲的發展。
GM的目標事項、原則、和動作，就跟傷害、屬性或HP一樣，同樣屬於規則的一部份。也因此，若你打算修改它們的運作方式或忽略它們，你必須像對待其他規則一樣小心地處理它們。
如何擔任GM當你以GM的身分在桌邊坐下時，你需要做這些事情：
描述故事情境遵守規則使用動作善用你的事前準備玩家們要做的事比較簡單──他們只需要說出他們角色會說的話、所想的事、以及會採取的行動。你的任務稍微困難一點，你必須說出除此之外的所有一切。這代表什麼意思呢？
首先，也是最重要的，你需要隨時描述玩家們周遭環境的即時狀況。這同時是你讓聚會開始的方法，也是當你打算在短暫的休息後、或開了個有趣的玩笑之後讓故事回到正軌時所需要做的事情：用清晰具體的詞彙告訴玩家他們身處於什麼樣的情境中。
利用細節和感官描述來讓玩家身歷其境。情境並不僅僅是「一頭獸人朝你衝鋒」，而是「一頭渾身浴血的獸人揮舞重槌，怒吼著朝你衝鋒而來」。你也可以反過來利用零碎的訊息來營造氣氛，比如說僅僅給出金屬鎧甲碰撞的噪音、或事拖著腳走路發出的足音。
玩家身邊的情境鮮少會是「一切都很好，什麼都不用擔心」。他們是正在經歷冒險的冒險者──給他們一些東西去應付！
當你描述情境時，永遠記得以「你打算做什麼？」結尾。地城世界是個充滿動作場景與冒險的遊戲，描繪出一個要求玩家們立即做出反應的情境吧！
確保你從一開始就遵守規則。這裡指的是你的GM動作，當然，但也記得時時注意玩家們的動作是否符合規則進行。每個人都有責任去注意某個動作是否有被觸發，這也包括你在內。當某個玩家的行動看起來像是準備觸發一條規則的時候，請他暫停描述，並詢問確認他們是否打算要這麼做。
進行動作是你需要遵守的其中一部分規則。你的GM動作與玩家截然不同，我們稍後會再仔細地介紹這些動作。你的動作會明確定義你能做的事情，並藉此改變遊戲的流向。
在上述這些環節中，同時也要記得善用你的事前準備。有時候你會知道一些玩家們還不知道的情報，你可以利用這些情報來協助你進行動作。當法師在施法的同時引來了不必要的注意，玩家們還不會知道他們引來的注意是什麼，但你很清楚，就在兩層樓之下，那可怖惡魔的不祥視線已經落在他們身上。
目標事項 (Agenda)Your agenda makes up the things you aim to do at all times while GMing a game of Dungeon World:
Portray a fantastic worldFill the characters’ lives with adventurePlay to find out what happensEverything you say and do at the table (and away from the table, too) exists to accomplish these three goals and no others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>