<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Classes on 地城世界 HTML SRD</title>
    <link>./classes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Classes on 地城世界 HTML SRD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="./classes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleric Spells</title>
      <link>./classes/cleric/spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/cleric/spells/</guid>
      <description>RotesEvery time you commune, you gain access to all of your rotes without having to select them or count them toward your allotment of spells.
Light	Rote
An item you touch glows with divine light, about as bright as a torch. It gives off no heat or sound and requires no fuel but is otherwise like a mundane torch. You have complete control of the color of the flame. The spell lasts as long as it is in your presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moves in Detail</title>
      <link>./classes/class_moves_discussion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/class_moves_discussion/</guid>
      <description>Moves in DetailMulticlass MovesMulticlass DabblerMulticlass InitiateMulticlass MasterFor the purposes of these multiclass moves the cleric’s commune and cast a spell count as one move. Likewise for the wizard’s spellbook, prepare Spells, and cast a Spell.
When you first select a multiclass move that grants you the ability to cast spells you prepare and cast spells as if you had one level in the casting class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bard</title>
      <link>./classes/bard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/bard/</guid>
      <description>The BardThe poems say an adventurer’s life is all open roads and the glory of coin and combat. The tales told in every farmhand-filled inn have to have some ring of truth to them, don’t they? The songs to inspire peasantry and royals alike—to soothe the savage beast or drive men to a frenzy—have to come from somewhere.
Enter the bard. You, with your smooth tongue and quick wit. You teller-of-tales and singer-of-songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cleric</title>
      <link>./classes/cleric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/cleric/</guid>
      <description>The ClericThe lands of Dungeon World are a gods-forsaken mess. They’re lousy with the walking dead, beasts of all sorts, and the vast unnatural spaces between safe and temple-blessed civilizations. It is a godless world out there. That’s why it needs you.
Bringing the glory of your god to the heathens isn’t just in your nature—it’s your calling. It falls to you to proselytize with sword and mace and spell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Druid</title>
      <link>./classes/druid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/druid/</guid>
      <description>The DruidCast your eyes around the fire. What has brought you to these people, stinking of the dust and sweat of the city? Perhaps it is a kindness—do you protect them as the mother bear watches over her cubs? Are they your pack, now? Strange brothers and sisters you have. Whatever your inspiration, they would certainly fail without your sharp senses and sharper claws.
You are of the sacred spaces; you are born of soil and wear the marks of her spirits on your skin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fighter</title>
      <link>./classes/fighter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/fighter/</guid>
      <description>The FighterIt’s a thankless job—living day to day by your armor and the skill of your arm. To dive heedlessly into danger. They won’t be playing golden horns for the time you took that knife to the ribs for them in the bar in Bucksberg. No flock of angels to sing of the time you dragged them, still screaming, from the edge of the Pits of Madness, no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Paladin</title>
      <link>./classes/paladin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/paladin/</guid>
      <description>The PaladinHell awaits. An eternity of torment in fire or ice or whatever best suits the sins of the damned throngs of Dungeon World. All that stands between the pits of that grim torture and salvation is you. Holy man, armored war machine, templar of the Good and the Light, right? The cleric may say his prayers at night to the gods, dwelling in their heavens. The fighter may wield his sharp sword in the name of “good” but you know.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Ranger</title>
      <link>./classes/ranger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/ranger/</guid>
      <description>The RangerThese city-born folk you travel with. Have they heard the call of the wolf? Felt the winds howl in the bleak deserts of the East? Have they hunted their prey with the bow and the knife like you? Hell no. That’s why they need you.
Guide. Hunter. Creature of the wilds. You are these things and more. Your time in the wilderness may have been solitary until now, but the call of some greater thing—call it fate if you like—has cast your lot with these folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Thief</title>
      <link>./classes/thief/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/thief/</guid>
      <description>The ThiefYou’ve heard them, sitting around the campfire. Bragging about this battle or that. About how their gods are smiling on your merry band. You count your coins and smile to yourself—this is the thrill above all. You alone know the secret of Dungeon World—filthy filthy lucre.
Sure, they give you lip for all the times you’ve snuck off alone but without you, who among them wouldn’t have been dissected by a flying guillotine or poisoned straight to death by some ancient needle trap?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wizard</title>
      <link>./classes/wizard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/wizard/</guid>
      <description>The WizardDungeon World has rules. Not the laws of men or the rule of some petty tyrant. Bigger, better rules. You drop something—it falls. You can’t make something out of nothing. The dead stay dead, right?
Oh, the things we tell ourselves to feel better about the long, dark nights.
You’ve spent so very long poring over those tomes of yours. The experiments that nearly drove you mad and all the botched summonings that endangered your very soul.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizard Spells</title>
      <link>./classes/wizard/spells/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>./classes/wizard/spells/</guid>
      <description>Wizard SpellsCantripsYou prepare all of your cantrips every time you prepare spells without having to select them or count them toward your allotment of spells.
Light	Cantrip
An item you touch glows with arcane light, about as bright as a torch. It gives off no heat or sound and requires no fuel, but it is otherwise like a mundane torch. You have complete control of the color of the flame.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>